Ivan Poliakov

LinkedIn | GitHub | Codeforces

Email: ivan.polyakov.01@gmail.com

Mobile: +31 627 21 72 51

Location: Maastricht, Limburg, The Netherlands

SUMMARY

I am a machine learning engineer specializing in Deep Learning, Generative AI, algorithmic optimization and mathematics, primarily writing code in C++, Python and C. I have 1 year of work experience in AI industry and am currently working on several ongoing research projects as a part of my MSc degree in AI at Maastricht University while seeking new job opportunities.



TECHNICAL SKILLS

Domain Knowledge : Algorithm design and optimization, Deep Learning, Generative AI,

LLMs and Agents, NLP, Computer Vision,

Probability and Mathematical Optimization, Multithreading

Programming Languages: C++, Python, C, Java

Machine Learning : PyTorch, NumPy, SciPy, scikit-learn, LangChain

Development : C++ STL, REST API, Flask, Django, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, PyQt, React.js

Platforms & Tools : Google Cloud Platform, Git, Linux, Docker, CMake, gradle, Google Test, Bash

Data & Visualization : pandas, OpenCV, Matplotlib, seaborn

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

ML engineer Sep 2024 – Jan 2024

Stealth Startups Remote – USA

Building product prototypes that revolve around data mining, agentic workflows and latest AI research.

NLP Engineer (internship)

Aug 2021 – Dec 2021

Garant Remote - Moscow, Russia

- Built a minimalistic library for working with common text processing techniques.
- Designed a Q&A model for a set of common user queries.

EDUCATION

Maastricht University

Maastricht University

Maastricht, Limburg, The Netherlands

Feb 2024 – present

Master of Artificial Intelligence – ongoing research

Maastricht, Limburg, The Netherlands

Bachelor of Data Science and Artificial Intelligence – thesis on GANs

2019-2022

PROJECTS AND ACTIVITIES

Mini-renderer C++ Repository

- Independently developed a 3D renderer with zero dependencies in C++, supporting camera view, lighting, and shading techniques.
- Can render a 2500-face model on a standard ThinkPad CPU in < 150ms.

Tetris with Autoplay Java Repository

• Led the development of a Tetris game and auto-play powered by a genetic algorithm for a university team project.

Juice Pong Robot Python, YOLO

• Developed a throwing strategy for a university lab project: a robotic setup that plays "juice pong," featuring a custom 3D-printed spoon and YOLO-based overhead camera tracking.

Competitive Programming

C++, Python, stress-testing

Codeforces profile

- Qualified for the Russian Olympiad in Informatics national finals in 2019.
- Achieved Master rank on Codeforces in 2021 and founded the first team from my university to compete at ICPC NWERC in 2024.
- Coached dozens of students one-on-one and in group settings.